Guide to the Brasch Family Collection, 1891-1920
Department of Special Collections
Brasch Family Collection,
1891-1920
Special Collections M0176
Brasch family.
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Max Brasch, 1967.
Scope and Content
This collection consists mainly of letters written by the children of Otto and Caroline Brasch to their brother Frederick E. Brasch. They date from 1891 through 1920, and originate from San Jose, Santa Clara, San Francisco, and Hawaii. The letters from Caroline Brasch describe the San Francisco Earthquake in 1906, and there is also included among the letters an account of a camping trip made by Frederick and Max Brasch and a friend to the ocean at pescadero and Santa Cruz in 1894.
Biographical Note
Otto and Caroline Brasch had immigrated from Germany sometime during the 1870's and gave encouragement to their children to improve themselves by the writing of letters. Information concerning the background of the family may be found in the brief and incomplete biography written by Frederick E. Brasch and included in this collection.
The Brasch family consisted of the following persons: Otto and Caroline Brasch
Frederick Edward Brasch (1875-1967)
Maxwell P. (originally Maximillian)
George
Samuel
Betty (Mrs. Joseph Picard)
Caroline (used spelling of Carolyn)
Augusta (Mrs. A. E. Acton, San Francisco)
Louise (Mrs. Albert Schmidt)
Walter
Louis Brasch (brother of Otto)
George and Marie Johannesen (Portland, Oregon) Walter (son)
Fritz and Marie Johannesen - George and Fritz are the brothers of Caroline Brasch (Mrs. Otto)
Mamie
Alice
Arthur
Carl
Frederick Brasch was a student at Stanford from 1897 to 1899 and was later employed in the Stanford Library (1912 - 1916). He was a noted astronomer and bibliographer.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1891-Dec 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. 12 Jan 1891to Freddie from George Johannsen
  - 2. 31 Dec 1891to Freddie & May from Mamie Johannsen
  - 3. 11 Apr 1892to Freddie from Mamie Johannson
  - 4. 15 Apr 1892to Freddie & Max from Mamie Johannson
  - 5. 16 June 1892to Freddie & Max from Mamie Johannson
  - 6. 24 June 1892to Freddie & Max from Mamie Johannson
  - 7. 20 Aug 1892to Fred from Mamie Johannson
  - 8. 14 Feb 1892to Freddie & Max from Mamie Johannson
  - 9. 16 Dec 1892to Fred from Mamie Johannson
  - 10. 10 Feb 1893to Fred from George Johannson
  - 11. 5 May 1893to Fred from [?]
  - 12. 5 May 1893to Freddie & Max from Alice
  - 13. 20 Dec 1893to Fred from George
  - 14. 13 Mar 1894to Freddie from Mamie
  - 15. 11 May 1894to F. E. Brasch from Ferdinand Bach
  - 16. 22 July 1894to Fred from Alice Johannson
  - 17. 10 Aug 1894to F. E. Brasch from Ferdinand Bach
  - 18. 20 Aug 1894to Fred from Alice
  - 19. 19 Sept 1894 Camp de Jolby&s Trip-an account of a wagon trip made by several boys through the Santa Cruz Mountains-much local color, stylistic interest, signed by Fred E. Brasch, A. J. Snvergent[?] and Max Brasch
  - 20. 2 Mar 1895to Fred from Caroline Brasch
  - 21. 5 May 1895to Fred from Alice J.
    [UNK]
  - 22. 10 May 1895to Fred from Alice J.
  - 23. 4 July 1895to [?] (her son) from C. W. Brasch
  - 24. 5 July 1895to Fred from Caroline
  - 25. 18 July 1895to F. F. Brasch from Ferd. Bach
  - 26. 22 July 1895to [?] (her son) from C. W. Brasch
  - 27. 1 Aug 1895to Fred from Max
  - 28. 25 Aug 1895to Fred from Max
  - 29. 9 Sept 1895to Fred from George
  - 30. 13 Oct. 1895to Fred from Max
  - 31. 13 Oct. 1895to Fred from George O. Brasch
  - 32. 10 Nov. 1895to Fred from George Brasch
  - 33. 16 Nov. 1895to Fred from Carolyn Brasch
  - 34. 11 Dec. 1895to Frity from C. Brasch (in German)
  - 35. 30 Dec 1895to Fred from Agusta Brasch
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1896-Sept 1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. 16 Jan 1896to [?] frp, [?] (in German)
  - 2. 2 Mar 1896to [Fred?] from Max
  - 3. 30 Mar 1896to F. E. Brasch from George Johannson
  - 4. 11 Apr 1896to Fred from Marie J.
  - 5. 28 Apr. 1896to Fred from Caroline
  - 6. 28 Apr. 1896to Fred from Caroline
  - 7. 14 May 1896to [Fred?] from Max
  - 8. 27 May 1896to Fred from Frank J. Reinegger
  - 9. 2 June 1896to Fred from Max Brasch
  - 10. 2 June 1896to [Fred or Max?] from Caroline
  - 11. 16 July 1896to Fred from Caroline Brasch
  - 12. 19 July 1896to Fred from Frank J. Reinegger
  - 13. 29 Aug. 1896to Fred from George Brasch
  - 14. 1 Sept 1896to Fred from Max
  - 15. 20 Sept. 1896to Fred from C. W. Brasch
  - 16. 3 Oct. 1896to [Fred?] from Max
  - 17. 4 Nov 1896to Fred from George Brasch
  - 18. 4 Nov. 1896to Fred from Samuel B.
  - 19. 4 Nov 1896to Fred from Max Brasch
  - 20. 23 Nov. 1896to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 21. 16 Dev 1896to Fred from Caroline
  - 22. 20 Dec. 1896to Fred from Frank J. Reinegger
  - 23. 11 Jan 1897to F.R. BRasch from F. Bach
  - 24. 13 Jan 1897to Fred from Max Brasch
  - 25. 28 Feb 1897to [?] from C. W. Brasch
  - 26. 4 Mar 1897to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 27. 4 Mar 1897to [Fred?] from Max
  - 28. 13 Mar 1897to [Fred?] from Max Brasch
  - 29. 15 Mar 1897to Fred from George
  - 30. [] Apr 1897to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 31. 16 Apr 1897to [Fred?] from Max Brasch
  - 32. 21 Apr 1897to [Fred?] from Max Brasch
  - 33. 21 Apr 1897to Fred from George Brasch
  - 34. 15 May 1897to Fred from Max Brasch
  - 35. 1 June 1897to F. R. Brasch from F. Brasch
  - 36. 7 June 1897to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 37. 8 June 1897to [her sister] from Betty
  - 38. 8 July 1897to [?] from [] (in German)
  - 39. 9 July 1897to [?] from [?]
  - 40. 7 Oct. 1897to Fred from Marie
  - 41. 1 Sept 1897to Fred from Marie
- Correspondence Jan 1898-Dec. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. 14 Jan 1898to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 2. 15 Jan 1898to [?] from [?]
  - 3. 20 Jan 1898to Fred from Marie Johannsen
  - 4. 6 Feb 1898to [Fred?] from M. R. Brasch
  - 5. 6 Feb 1898to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 6. 6 Feb 1898to [Fred?] from George
  - 7. 10 Feb 1898to Fred from Marie J.
  - 8. 14 Mar 1898to Fred from Alice Johanneen
  - 9. 25 Mar 1898to Fred from Max Brasch
  - 10. 12 Apr 1898to Fred from M. R. Brasch
  - 11. 20 Apr 1898to [Fred?] from [?]
  - 12. 20 Apr. 1898to [Fred?] from George
  - 13. 21 May 1898to [Fred?] from George
  - 14. 22 June 1898to [Fred?] from Max Brasch
  - 15. 3 July 1898to Fred from Marie J.
  - 16. 6 Oct 1898to Fred from [?]
  - 17. 13 Nov 1898to [Fred?] from Betty
  - 18. 17 Nov 1898to Fred from Caroline
  - 19. 20 Jan 1899to Fred from George
  - 20. 21 Jan 1899to Fred from Marie Johannsen
  - 21. 22 Jan 1899to [?] from Otto Brasch
  - 22. 22 Jan 1899to [Fred?] from Betty
  - 23. 14 Feb. 1899to Fred from Caroline
  - 24. 24 Feb 1899to Fred from M. R. Brasch
  - 25. 4 Apr 1899to Fred from Betty
  - 26. 12 Apr 1899to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 27. 30 Apr. 1899to Fred from Laurolal S. Woodhams
  - 28. 2 May 1899to [Fred?] from M. P. Brasch
  - 29. 17 May 1899to [Fred?] from Caroline
  - 30. 19 June 1899to Fred from Mamie
  - 31. 12 Nov 1899to Fred from Sam
  - 32. 29 Aug. 1899to Fred from Carrie
  - 33. [?] Dec 1899to Fred from Mamie
- CORRESPONDENCE Feb 1900-Dec 1900 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. 12 Feb 1900to Fritz from O. W. Brasch
  - 2. 15 Mar 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 3. 28 Mar 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 4. 1 Apr 1900to Freddie from Carolyn
  - 5. 7 Apr 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 6. 19 Apr 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 7. 28 Apr 1900to Fred from Carolyn
  - 8. 1 May 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 9. 17 May 1900to [Fred?] from Louise
  - 10. 17 May 1900to [Fred?] from George
  - 11. 29 June 1900to [Fred?] from Carolyn
  - 12. 30 June 1900to Fred from C. W. Brasch
  - 13. 3 July 1900to Fred from Marie
  - 14. 6 Aug 1900to Fred from Carolyn
  - 15. 26 Aug 1900to Fred from Carolyn
  - 16. 2 Sept 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. R. Brasch
  - 17. 8 Sept 1900to Fred from Carolyn
  - 18. 27 Sept 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 19. 12 Oct 1900to [Fred?] from [?]
  - 20. 17 Oct 1900to F. E. Brasch from M. P. Brasch
  - 21. 31 Oct 1900to [Fred?] from M. P. Brasch
  - 22. 20 Dec. 1900to Fred from George
  - 23. 21 Dec 1900to Fred from Marie
- Correspondence Feb 1901-Dec 1902 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1. 6 Feb 1901to Fred from Marie
  - 2. 11 Feb 1901to Fred from Otto Brasch
  - 3. 9 Apr 1901to Fred from Ferdinand Bach
  - 4. 29 Apr 1901to Fred from Carolyn
  - 5. 27 July 1901to Fred from M. P. Brasch
  - 6. 7 Aug 1901to Fred from Agusta
  - 7. 7 Aug 1901to Fred from Carolyn
  - 8. 26 Aug 1901to Fred from Alice
  - 9. 23 Aug 1901to Fred from Marie
  - 10. 14 Nov 1901to Fred from Marie
  - 11. 21 Dec 1901to Fred from Mamie
  - 12. 22 Dec 1901to Fred from Marie
  - 13. 24 Dec. 1901to Fred from Otto Brasch
  - 14. 2 Jan 1902to Fred from Agusta
  - 15. 16 Jan 1902to Fred from Louise
  - 16. 25 Jan 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 17. 28 Jan 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 18. [?] Jan 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 19. 5 Mar 1902to Fred from Otto Brasch
  - 20. 18 Apr 1902to Sniggelfritz from Carolyn
  - 21. 2 June 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 22. [?] June 1902to Fred from [Otto?]
  - 23. 4 July 1902to Fred from Mamie
  - 25. 6 Oct. 1902to Fred from Augusta
  - 26. 13 Oct 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 27. 17 Oct 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 28. 31 Oct 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 29. 20 Nov 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 30. 1 Dec. 1902to Fred from Carolyn
  - 31. 4 Dec 1902to Fred from [Otto?]
  - 32. 20 Dec 1902to Fred from Annie
  - 33. 29 Dec 1902to Fred from Carolyn
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1903-Dec 1903 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1. 26 Jan 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 2. 14 Feb 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 3. 19 Feb 1903to Fred from Otto
  - 4. 4 Mar 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 5. 12 Mar 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 6. 6 Apr 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 7. 13 Apr 1903to Fred from Otto
  - 8. 20 Apr 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 9. 25 Apr 1903to Fred from Marie
  - 10. 26 Apr 1903to Fred from Marie
  - 11. 28 May 1903to Fred from M. P. Brasch
  - 12. 14 May 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 13. 28 May 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 14. 12 June 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 15. 13 July 1903to Fred from Otto
  - 16. 1 Aug 1903to Fred from Louise
  - 17. 4 Aug 1903to Fred from Augusta
  - 18. 10 Aug 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 19. 13 Aug 1903to Fred from [Annie?]
  - 20. 22 Aug 1903to Alphonse from Carolyn
  - 21. [?] Aug 1903to Fred from Louise
  - 22. 20 Sept. 1903to Alphonse from Carolyn
  - 23. 30 Sept 1903to Fred from Louise
  - 24. 14 Oct 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 25. 5 Oct 1903to Fred from Marie
  - 26. 11 Oct 1903to Fred from [?]
  - 27. 25 Oct 1903to Fred from Louise
  - 28. [?] Oct 1903to Fred from Otto
  - 29. [?] Oct 1903to Fred frm Otto
  - 30. 12 Nov 1903to Fred from Carolyn
  - 31. 15 Nov 1903to Fred from Augusta
  - 32. 30 Nov 1903to Fred frm Carolyn
  - 33. [?] Nov 1903to Fred from Annie
  - 34. 28 Dec 1903to Fred from [Nora?]
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1904-Dec 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1. 4 Jan 1904to Fred from Carolyn
  - 2. 15 Jan 1904to Fred from Carolyn
  - 3. [?] Jan 1904to Fred from Otto
  - 4. 4 Feb 1904to Fred from Carolyn
  - 5. 18 Feb 1904to Fred from Marie
  - 6. 24 Feb 1904to Fred from Carolyn
  - 7. 5 Apr. 1904to Fred from Annie Brasch
  - 8. 7 Apr 1904to Fred from Carolyn
  - 9. 18 Apr 1904to Fred from Betty
  - 10. 25 Apr 1904to Fred from Augusta
  - 11. 2 May 1904to Fred from Max
  - 12. 28 July 1904to Fred from Augusta
  - 13. 12 Sept 1904to Fred from Carolyn
  - 14. 15 Dec 1904to Fred from Otto
  - 15. 23 May 1905to Fred from Otto (answered on this date)
  - 16. 4 Dec 1905to Fred from Louise
  - 17. 4 Dec 1905to Fred from Louise
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1906-Nov 1908 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1. 14 Jan 1906to Fred from Louise
  - 2. 1 Apr 1906to Fred-Greetings from L. Bridges
  - 3. 6 May 1906to Fred from Carolyn-account of earthquake, fire, and ensuing misery
  - 4. 24 May 1906to Fred from Augusta
  - 5. 9 July 1906to Fred from Louise
  - 6. 14 Sept 1906to Fred from Max Brasch
  - 7. 25 Nov 1906to Fred from Otto
  - 8. 22 Feb 1906to Fred from Otto
  - 9. 26 July 1907to Fred from Otto
  - 10. 14 Nov. 1907to Fred from Otto
  - 11. 9 Dec 1907to Fred from Otto
  - 12. 27 Jan 1908to Fred from Otto
  - 13. 18 Mar 1908to Fred from Marie
  - 14. 29 June 1908to Fred from Otto
  - 15. 31 July 1908to Fred from Carolyn (death of Carl Johannsen)
  - 16. 26 Sept 1908to Fred from Otto
  - 17. 7 Nov 1908to Fred from George
- Correspondence Mar 1908-May 1909 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1. 27 Mar 1908to Fred from Otto
  - 2. 27 May 1909to Fred from Otto
  - 3. 17 June 1909to Fred from Louise
  - 4. 15 June 1909to Fred from Otto
  - 5. 25 June 1909to Fred from Louise
  - 6. 20 June 1909to Fred from Max
  - 7. 28 July 1909to Fred from Max
  - 8. 2 Sept 1909to Fred from Max
  - 9. 17 Sept 1909to Fred from Otto
  - 10. 29 Sept 1909to Fred from Louise
  - 11. 29 Nov. 1909to Fred from Gus
  - 12. [?] Nov 1909to Fred from Marie
  - 13. 23 May 1909to Fred from Annie
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1910-Dec 1910 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1. 5 Jan 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 2. 20 Jan 1910to Fred from Gus
  - 3. 8 Feb 1910to Fred from Otto
  - 4. 31 Mar. 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 5. 4 Apr 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 6. 7 Apr 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 7. 12 Apr 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 8. 13 Apr 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 9. 14 Apr 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 10. 15 Apr. 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 11. 20 Apr 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 12. [?] Apr[?] 1910to Fred from Louise
  - 13. 24 May 1910to Fred from Gus
  - 14. 20 June 1910to Fred from [?]
  - 15. 19 July 1910to Fred from Gus
  - 16. 15 Sept 1910to Fred from W. G. Johannsen
  - 17. 26 Sept 1910to Fred from Gus
  - 18. 7 Oct 1910to Fred from Gus
  - 19. 18 Nov 1910to Fred from Otto
  - 20. 31 Nov 1910to Fred from L. Bridges
  - 21. 2 Dec 1910to Fred from Gus
  - 22. [?] [?] 1910to Fred from Louise
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1911-Dec 1911 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1. 4 Jan 1911to Fred from Max
  - 2. 8 Jan 1911to Fred from Max
  - 3. 13 Jan 1911to Fred from Max
  - 4. 16 Jan 1911to Fred from Otto
  - 5. 25 Jan 1911to Fred from Walter
  - 6. 15 Feb 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 7. 23 Feb 1911to Fred from Gus
  - 8. 9 Mar 1911to Fred from The Saucy Kid
  - 9. 3 Apr 1911to Fred from Otto
  - 10. 5 May 1911to Fred from Mamie
  - 11. 17 May 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 12. 18 May 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 13. 27 July 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 14. 3 Aug 1911to Fred from [Aunty?]
  - 15. 16 Aug 1911to Fred from [?]
  - 16. 3 Aug 1911to Fred from Gus
  - 17. 16 Aug 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 18. 23 Aug 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 19. 5 Sept 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 20. 13 Sept 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 21. 22 Sept 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 22. 29 Sept 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 23. 8 Nov 1911to Fred from Otto
  - 24. 27 Nov 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 25. 10 Dec 1911to Fred from Gus
  - 26. 15 Dec 1911to Fred from Louise
  - 27. 21 Dec 1911to Fred from Auntie
  - 28. 27 Dec 1911to Fred from Louise
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1912-Oct 1912 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1. 23 Jan 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 2. 2 Feb 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 3. 21 Feb 1912to Fred from Gus
  - 4. 21 Feb 1912to Fred from Max
  - 5. 23 Feb 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 6. 30 Mar 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 7. 8 Apr 1912to Fred from Caroline
  - 8. 12 Apr 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 9. 1 May 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 10. 24 May 1912to Fred from Max
  - 11. 4 June 1912to Fred from Gus
  - 12. 8 June 1912to Fred from Otto
  - 13. 8 June 1912to Fred from Albert & Louise
  - 14. [?] June 1912to Fred from Nona
  - 15. 11 July 1912to Fred from Max
  - 16. 31 July 1912to Fred from Louise
  - 17. 7 Aug 1912to Fred from Max
  - 18. 7 Oct 1912to fred from Auntie
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1913-Dec 1914 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1. 7 Jan 1913to Fred from Max
  - 2. 14 Jan 1913to Fred from Auntie
  - 3. 27 Jan 1913to Fred from Gus
  - 4. 24 Feb 1913to Fred from Gus
  - 5. 2 Sept 1913to Fred from Gus
  - 6. 24 Nov 1913to Fred from Gus
  - 7. 19 Dec 1913to Fred from Auntie
  - 8. 30 Dec 1913to Fred from Otto
  - 9. 5 Jan 1913to Fred from Otto
  - 10. 17 Feb 1914to Fred from The Trio
  - 11. 6 Feb 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 12. 12 Mar 1914to Fred from Max
  - 13. 23 Mar 1914to Fred from Otto
  - 14. 3 May 1914to Fred from Max
  - 15. 13 June 1914to Fred from Mamie
  - 16. 15 June 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 17. 19 June 1914to Fred from Otto
  - 18. 22 July 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 19. 21 Sept 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 20. 20 Nov 1914to Fred from Otto
  - 21. 19 Dec 1914to Fred from Albert & Louise
  - 22. 21 Dec 1914to Fred from Auntie
  - 23. 26 Dec 1914to Fred from Albert & Louise
  - 24. [?] [?] 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 25. [?] [?] 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 26. [?] [?] 1914to Fred from Louise
  - 27. [?] [?] 1914to Fred from Louise
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1915-Oct 1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1. 29 Jan 1915to Fred from Joe & Betty
  - 2. 11 Feb 1915to Fred from Otto
  - 3. 25 May 1915to Fred from Elsie
  - 4. 26 May 1915to Fred from [?] (page missing)
  - 5. 29 May 1915to Fred from Max
  - 6. 20 July 1915to Fred from George
  - 7. 3 Sept 1915to Fred from Marie
  - 8. 12 Sept 1915to Fred from Betty
  - 9. 23 Sept 1915to Fred from Louise & Albert
  - 10. 28 Sept 1915to Fred from Max
  - 11. 1 Oct 1915to Fred from Mamie
  - 12. 3 Oct 1915to Fred from Betty & Joe
  - 13. 7 Oct 1915to Fred from Marie
  - 14. 18 Oct 1915to Fred from Elsie
  - 15. 8 Nov 1915to Fred from Frank Brasch
  - 16. 21 Dec 1915to Fred from Walter
  - 17. 22 Dec 1915to Fred from Walter
  - 18. 30 Dec 1915to Fred from Otto
  - 19. 4 Feb 1916to Fred from Max
  - 20. 28 Feb 1916to Fred from Joe & Betty
  - 21. 14 Mar 1916to Fred from Joe & Betty
  - 22. 14 Mar 1916to Fred from Nona
  - 23. 25 Mar 1916to Fred from Otto
  - 24. 14 May 1916to Fred from Auntie
  - 25. 31 May 1916to Fred from George
  - 26. 8 Aug 1916to Fred from Louise & Albert
  - 27. 16 Sept 1916to Fred from Otto
  - 28. 21 Sept 1916to Fred from Louise
  - 29. 25 Oct 1916to Fred from Otto
- CORRESPONDENCE Jan 1917-June 1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1. 5 Jan 1917to Fred from Ferdinand Bach
  - 2. 23 Jan 1917to Fred from Otto
  - 3. 20 Fab 1917to Fred from Otto
  - 4. 13 Apr 1917to Fred from Elsie
  - 5. 25 Apr 1917to Fred from [?]
  - 6. 11 June 1917to Fred from Otto
  - 7. 12 June 1917to Fred from Walter
  - 8. 28 Sept 1917to Fred from Max
  - 9. 1)ct 1917to Fred from Louise & Albert
  - 10. 5 Oct 1917to Fritzie from Otto
  - 11. 5 Oct 1917to Fred from Otto
  - 12. 26 Dec 1917to Fred from Otto
  - 13. 7 Jan 1918to Fred fr m Louise & Albert
  - 14. 17 June &23to Fred from Gus acton-Death of Louise Brasch
- MISC PIECES (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1. [no date]to Fred from Louise & Albert
  - 2. [no date]hand written paper by Otto Brasch entitled Where is American Dignity and Honor
  - 3. [no date]to Fred from Otto
  - 4. [no date]to Fred from Nona
  - 5. [no date]to Fred from Annie
  - 6. [no date]to Fred from Aunt Annie
  - 7. [no date]to Fred from Otto
  - 8. [no date]to Fred from Uncle Louis
  - 9. [no date]to Fred from Louise (fragment)
  - 10. envelope addressed to F. E. Brasch-1 June 1916
  - 11. hand copied poem entitled Requiem by Johannes Brahme-Opus 45
  - 12. [no date]to Fred from Caroline Brasch
  - 1. Biography of F. E. Brasch, pp. 1-45 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1. Biography of F. E. Brasch, pp. 45-finish (Box 2, Folder 8)
- MISC (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1. clipping, Feb 1906,relating bicyble accident of Alice & Cecelia Brasch (source unknown)
  - 2. April 19 1906edition of The Call Chronicle Examiner- earthquake issue
  - 3. April 19, 1906-map of the destruction of San Francisco
  - 4. July 2, 1906edition of The Call- murder of Caroline Brasch
  - 1. 15 Apr 1906edition San Francisco Examiner- 50 years after the fire (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2. 18 Apr 1906edition of People-supplement of the S. F. Examiner
  - 3. 15 Apr 1906-attitude on earthquake by Kathleen Norris in The American Weekly
  - 4. 18 Apr 1906edition of The San Francisco Chronicle- earthquake edition
  - 5. Clipping from an unknown source re: library help
  - 6. My own shall come to me John Borroughs
  - 7. clipping from an unknown source re: how to make a 30 cent telescope
  - 1. Samuel [Struct?]-, photo (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 2. Brasch family- 1903, photo
  - 3. Otto Brasch-, photo
  - 4. Photo Album of San Francisco
  - 5. The Fleet at San Francisco
  - 6. San Francisco the imperishable
  - 7. San Francisco the imperishable issued by the Southern Pacific Company.
- MISCELIANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1. Oct. 1922-May 1960
  - 2. 9 items referring to Fredrick Brasch
- Addition, Nov. 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1. ApcS, March 8, 1915 Betty to Otto [Brasch]
  - 2. 2 photographs - Germany
  - 3. Marriage Certificate, Otto Brasch and Caroline Johannsen Mar. 1, 1875
  - 4. Citizenship papers of Otto Brasch, Aug. 5, 1884
  - 5. Safe passage Visa to Otto Brasch & his wife May 24, 1909(from U.S. State Dept.
  - 6. 10/16/[UNK] DHAN GOPAL MUKERJI TO MRS BRASCH (1890-1936), ALS